Dubbed Digimon is the undisputed greatest animated series of all time.
You may disagree with that
But I said undisputed, so you aren't allowed to
How was Digimon created?
Well, we don't know exactly how the original Digimon series was created
Because there's no documentation
But we do know how dubbed Digimon was made,
But I have to tell you this is a 100% true story
So don't disrespect Digimon by looking it up
It all started in 1998
Tokyo, Japan
When a couple of anime executives were going out.
Let me recreate the iconic moment.
Don't worry, I have a perfect Japanese accent.
Hey, Tony!
Yes it's me, Tony Gavalinguero[sp?]
Cool! We're going out for some sake and Gabba gooey. You coming?
I can't, ain't got the cash
Sell one of them anime rights to the country to the east of us, is a three-letter word
You have to remember, United States at the time, like they had landed on the moon
But they were still years away from creating
Halo, so it was still considered like a niche country.
It was just luck that he sold to them
Tony called his American contact, a respected man named Elijah 4Kids The Third
Who had taken over a dying company
Hey Elijah, you wanna buy one of these cartoons?
He did but could only afford one
For the repo man was knocking. Yes Mr Linguero,
I heard of one anime that could be interesting
It's called
Samurai Pizza Cats
Tonegawa was happy to hear that
Samurai Pizza Cats was and is considered the Godfather of anime, and he knew he could get a fat paycheck
Elijah, I would love to sell it to yous, but i'ma need
$400
I... I don't know if I can afford that.
Come on!
Tony put his hand on a barrel of tapes
I'll... throw in this, the popular series, the Di-ja-mon... the Di-ja-ma-mon...
Is this a Pokémon ripoff?
Elijah had to do it.
This was his last chance.
The 4Kids company dubbed Samurai Pizza Cats
But it never took off in America.
Critics loved it.
But the average Yank audience could not relate.
Too foreign.
Samurais are Japanese, pizza is Italian, and cats are Egyptian.
4Kids went broke.
His employees know
Former friends left him. A company that had dubbed anime for five generations
Dead. Elijah sat alone in the park with the last thing he owned: the tape Digimon
If I could only make you more American,
make you good...
But...
I don't believe in myself.
I think you can do it! Make it American, make it better!
There was someone sitting next to Elijah in the park.
Elijah realized this was no normal man, it was
Home video content creator Kilian Experience!
Listen, Elijah! Don't believe in yourself, believe in me!
Believe in the Kilian who believes in you!
Elijah 4Kids knew what he had to do
He went back to the office and worked all night and dubbed all of Digimon alone
He saved the company and created a series
I am now gonna spoil.
It starts with the climate around the world having a fit, and the main character going
Basically hundreds of millions of people and animals died, but I was at summer camps
It was alright, then it started to snow. In July!
We are introduced to the main characters.
Tai: doofus anime guy
Sora: She has a hat.
Matt: Serious anime guy
Izzy: computer nerd, but confident? So is not relatable
Mimi: Popular anime guy
Joe: also a nerd, but anxious, so that makes him more relatable
And T.K., he's Matt's kid brother
Today's canoeing was canceled, probably because camp staff were having panic attacks
Questioning if the world is ending, looking at the global economy collapsing.
They see the aurora borealis
That's cultural appropriation!
These things rain down. It's the 90's, smartphones barely exist yet
So they think it's a book
Haha! Reverse boomer'd you!
The tsunami kills them
The gang gets transferred to a digital world
Which today is a super overused trope in books, movies, animes, garbage fires.
But back then it was just an overused trope
Tai gets woken up by...
Uh... I didn't write down any Digimon names. This won't be a problem at all.
I shall guess.
Hi Tai, I'm PinkBallmon. I am your slave.
Izzy shows up
Where are we?
And Izzy's like "I have a theory"
And then he calls all of it on his first guess
This is to make it clear to the viewer that all the humans except Izzy will in general be useless
Which makes sense.
It's called Digimon, not Human-mons.
This is a pretty relaxing place.
No!
Giant monster bug with mandibles and fangs shows up to kill them
There's no relaxing here! In this world, you are not the apex predator anymore!
There is a 98% chance you're gonna die within the hour
Unfortunately, soon-to-be Bugmon shows them that some trees are just textures to save disk space
They're united and introduces themselves to each other.
I said, no relaxing!
The bug monster wants to first cut them into bits and then chew them into smaller bits
The Digimon get ready to fight.
Guys, don't charge the giant bug monster clearly designed to massacre!
You get learned, humans, In the DigiWorld, it's digi-kill or be digi-killed.
Then their digivices start to glow, and rainbow beams rain down from the sky
Turning the Digimon gay. No they evolved. Together, they can now do it!
Nope, realistic series. The bug man slaps them, and then he decides "I'm just gonna kill you all". So he does that.
Depressing ending for a series. Nah, that was the first episode
Episode 2: They didn't die!
So they fall down, and land on fish to soften the fall, as opposed to water.
"What do we do now," everyone says
Tai responds: "I saw the ocean. Let's go!"
Maybe we can find a boat!
In the undubbed version, he just says let's go to the ocean without a reason.
So good job, random dubber who decided to add character motivation.
On the beach, they find phone booths.
To children watching, the concept of phone booth is probably way more ridiculous
than being transferred to a digital world
And that's when they notice they're about to starve to death.
Tai notices that Joe conveniently has a bag filled with food.
He also has a Digimon who can talk to fish
They might be his friends, but he will obey orders
Ah shit, half hermit crab, half dinosaur is attacking us.
That's a lot of meat, let's kill it!
Sadly, they are too hungry to fight.
Tai's like, I've played Monster Hunter! Let's do this!
Ah, this is exactly like Monster Hunter!
When a Digidestined is in danger, that's when a Digimon evolves.
And Dinomon becomes a bigger Dinomon with a helmet. Evolved for biking.
Now, look at these sizes. In the Digimon series, sizes have no consistency in the slightest.
Which is awesome, and more shows should do that
Imagine Ice-T being a giant in random shots.
The show then says to hell with gravity also.
Now imagine if Ice-T suddenly started to float.
I told you this was a perfect show.
Ugh. Dinomon devolves back down.
Will admit, this hurts the series.
It would have been better if he permanently walked around with a giant dragon.
The next five episodes are all pretty much:
Let me have some character development!
Ahh, we're about to die!
Hey, someone not previously evolved, evolved!
Episode 3:
There's a tram in the middle of nowhere.
Who cares about that? My parents are divorced.
Ah, this lake has a sea monster!
Ah, my parents are divorced, and I'm in danger!
Ice, Ice, tiger!
Episode 4
I love you unconditionally, Sora!
I can't stand birds!
Then they see a flying gear. That's probably not important, but it penetrates a fire Pokémon.
What is important, there's a desert! Let's not go through there. It's called the desert because all life is dead.
They go through the desert and reach a village
Hello village! Sora is the greatest!
I can't stand birds!
The fire elemental is crazy!
I'll become a big bird and kill it!
Wow
I can stand birds now!
Episode 5: we are starving. It's hot, and our ears are working
Hey look! A factory! We can fix that last thing.
Izzy finds a battery and decides to charge his computer
Dumb millennial: at your age your great-grandparents didn't use factories to charge laptops.
They used them to lose their arms
It's a good way to lose weight
Then he enters the battery and the deciphers code that gives exposition.
He can decipher this code because he's adopted
Hey, a killer robot!
Aah, the robot is trying to kill us!
Hey guys, I've solved everything! Killer robots!
Bugmon transforms into NightmareCreatureMon!
There was a black gear in him. I am actually a nice Digimon. My chest contains missiles of friendship!
Episode 6: I miss home. This is really heartfelt.
I hope it doesn't get ruined by
Snails that throw poop!
In the original Japanese version, this was the only joke in the entire series.
Digimon was definitely a tax write-off.
Wanna go on a date, hot stuff?
No, I would never date you!
Because I'm a snail monster?
No, worse.
You are short!
The snail doesn't like that. But a teddy bear with laser eyes kills them.
It turns into a horror movie.
The bear turned the children into toys for toys
Now Mimi has to hunt. She calls for a charge from the Incelmon, then her plant becomes a... no.
Episode 7: We are starving and freezing
Hey, Fishstockmon?
Joe?
Just evolve, man. Let's get this arc over with.
Ok! Walrusmon!
That's the end of arc one.
The "we are trying not to die arc".
A black gear is being watched by
Oh god, I'm gonna have to censor this guy
This be... Yiffmon. He's in an eternal battle with a GreenMon.
But they are told to stop fighting by the first villain of the series
Well second villain, after their stomachs
The most evil Digimon
SixPackMon
He has the ability to corrupt people with fake supplement scams: the gears!
The two attack the kids, and look at this animation padding! Legends.
They escape and find the perfect hotel with food and everything.
Matt's like: you guys realize this is obviously a trap right?
We know Matt, but we're so tired of this. Let's just die.
Hahaha, this isn't a real hotel. It's my hotel-making illusion spell, that I never thought I would get to use!
Even the beds?
No, I assembled the beds myself. Got them suites in the non-fitting parts
But the beds splitting in parts was so demoralizing it gave me an idea.
I am splitting you up in parts
Yeah then the island too. Just to be sure.
You forgot to put me somewhere!
Right. YiffMon, cut his head off
But the Digiwatch has Norton 98 and an awakened YiffMon rescues him
Tai ends up on an iceberg and is attacked by a black gear polar bear.
He tries to throw DinoMon, but he can't because he is too heavy. So he kicks him and he flies.
This makes sense because programmers only programmed throwing physics. Perfect series.
Now nice polar bear helps them build an ice bridge
Meanwhile, Matt is in a cave and is getting sick for no particular reason
Because there's no proof that cold weather makes you sick.
Tai finds him, and they fight.
When one starts to cry, that's like when the teacher shows up, so you gotta stop.
But instead of a teacher, they are attacked by a HomelessMon
This is like the seventh time a cliff gets destroyed and they fall.
On the bear!
He has food, sick medicine
And defeats the enemy? And shows how to reverse the island? And the kids are the heroes?
Meanwhile, Izzy crashes and finds a ruin.
Hey, let's go find our friends
Bugmon, they're useless.
You know it, I know it, the audience knows it, and they wanna see me explore this ruin.
Meanwhile, Mimi gets into an attempted robbery by a poop Digimon that...
Let's skip this.
She made it to the ruin! Izzy!
Ah, it's the hot one. Neat.
Then he goes back to work.
Realizes that this ruin is a massive labyrinth
But he's being a bit too autistic
So Mimi starts to cry. Izzy! Do something!
Look, Bugmon, making women cry. It's what I do.
That was the final straw. She runs into the labyrinth.
There's a centaur here! Time to die, kid.
Minotaurs live in mazes, not centaurs.
No. Yes. No. Yes.
Fine, you win. Turns out this is a temple.
For the digi-devices. And they can shoot light beams
Still they need to turn this island around but no one is strong enough to change the gear
So Mimi kicks it, and it works, because like I said, kicking physics do not work
Meanwhile, the only guy with a sea Digimon landed in the sea. What luck.
Oh noes, he fell asleep.
Oh. Sora captured him. Joe is just the luckiest dude.
This island has a church
The current bad guy is a demon, and who better to fight him than JesusMon?
Instead, they find extra-ordinary creepy people with masks.
Hey kids, you wanna join our celebration?
No.
That was easy.
Meanwhile, T.K. falls into a waterfall, and then cries.
Like brother, like son.
The others faced freezing cold, tropical diseases, human eaters
T.K. ends up in a nursery, and anyone who has been to a nursery knows that it's 600 times worse
Digimon babies!
T.K. remembers being a baby.
I fell over on some blocks and then my brother told me that my clumsiness
Was the reason our parents were getting a divorce.
BabysitterMon asks them to leave,
and then BreadMon decides
No, I'm gonna fight you in a nursery! Worse than the villain, what's wrong with you?
Let's solve this with the former Olympic sport of tug of war. Bread wins, and they make up.
Unlike T.K.'s parents!
Hahaha!
It's time to take on the first villain. I wonder who will defeat him
Could it be the evolution that has been hinted in every episode?
Yiffmon shows up to destroy T.K.
Harder than he himself has been destroyed by furry artists.
Fortunately, the other Digidestined shows up just then
Supplements rained down, into the lion.
He's unstoppable!
Izzy comes in to save the day.
Tai! Our digi-devices have tasers.
We're saved!
Ok children. There's a prophecy that says humans will come to the island and destroy darkness.
We were hoping for like Navy SEALs, instead of Japanese kids, but whatever.
SixPackMon uses the gear on himself to become gigantic
But like sizes makes no sense in Digimon, so it's like whatever, man. What were you overcompensating for?
They attack simultaneously and get destroyed.
Only one left.
Oh, he just crushed him like nuts! Nasty!
Bread is evolving into... a hot guy, what?
"I want to take him home with me!"
Angemon was arrested by the FBI
Everyone give me your energy.
You can't just rip off Dragonball like that!
Yes, I can. Spirit Hand!
And SixPack is gone.
You may have defeated me angel, but the Digidestined are not truly safe
What do you mean?
They are not safe online.
Wait... are you-
You see, this video is sponsored by NordVPN.
We are currently dying. Is this really the right time?
It's always the right time to talk about internet security,
and NordVPN has military-grade encryption
Seriously?
And thousands of servers all over earth
If they click the link in the top of the description
And use the code kilianexperience, (Who?) they get 70% off a three-year plan
Ok link in top of the description. You done?
NordVPN - Probably only works on earth
A hologram appears.
Hi, I'm Gennai. Your Digimon can digivolve once more. You know, we gotta make more toys.
You need to gather these merchandi-, I mean pendants and crests.
They are on another continent, come here
Be sure you don't bring any diseases, didn't work out last time.
I have sent you a map, so you can leave the tutorial zone
It's pretty far how will they travel?
The people they have helped so far come together and build a raft
It immediately gets destroyed by a robotic whale that eats them
Churches? Angels? Being inside sea creatures?
This is just a Bible ripoff.
While stomach acid is slowly chewing on them
They destroy a gear and the whale blows them out of its blowhole.
And before you say, that's not how blow holes work
You don't know that. You've never been inside a whale, and a live whale.
Now they are talking to a creature the size of a football stadium that has the most casual voice
Apparently SixPackMon went through the trouble of hiding the pendants underwater, but was too lazy to find a good spot
So he picked the most convenient place: a convenience store. Tada!
Now they need to gather the crests.
The gang ends up in a village and it's obviously a trap set up by the next big villain
Orange chimpanzee hardware engineer Elvis
Yes
No size consistency. After they save the village, Elvis is like "I'm gonna artillery bomb this place"
And his stark net ability
drains the Digimon's power like Google Chrome
They run into a cave and here's the first crest how incredibly fortunate. What a happy ending
Their homes are ash
Running away from ElvisMon causes them to end up in desert number 400.
Tai is having a manic episode
And is trying to get his Dino to digivolve. By overfeeding him.
Then Joe gets a signal from a nearby coliseum.
They enter and it's a footbal- no wait, American dub.
It's a field of some exotic sport
And it's a trap. RabiesDinoMon and NormalDinoMon fight.
Rabies makes you stronger. Trust me on this one. Is this really happening?
Did I lick a toad? The floor of this exact goal was a crest!
Had they gone into the other goal, they would be dead!
Tai tries to get RabiesMon to kill him, to force his slave to evolve
Instead two other Digimon evolve to save him, and now it's three against one.
So like all the danger is gone, and that's when he evolves. But something went wrong!
SkeletoMon!
Electrocutes the other one, really kills him!
Then destroys everything, kicks everyone's ass, and passes out.
You know, like a drunk football hooligan!
Aah, DinoMon! I shouldn't have forced you to digivolve, you became a monster!
Bollocks! Look at the food Agumon ate! No protein!
No protein can't digivolve muscles.
Becomes a skeleton: Fact!
Once again, our main characters are dying in the desert.
The hologram man shows up again and says
You're all terrible pet owners!
That that's all he says.
A desert cruise ship driven by snails lets them on, and they get drunk off their minds
There's a man here who's actually a chicken
He never uses the fact that he can looked like a human, he shows up to them as a chicken
The monkey has a dance number
And then the cruise chases them, and as you expect, it hits a cactus and get launched into space!
None of this really happened, did it?
The Digidestined are having a heat stroke.
Still in the desert, still dying!
Tai is having massive confidence issues and
Not dead, mother-
Dead. A pixie killed him and is smiling about it.
This pixie is the hard Asian trainer trope
so he forces the Digidestined to break a plank,
tells Tai to go here and hallucinate
Then the writers remembers someone's gotta get a crest this episode, so they sent these two away.
TextureSwapMon attacks!
Tai hallucinating sees his young self, and tells him not to give up.
A huge me with a yellow dinosaur! What the actual-
That's when Tai realized he's in a pretty weird situation, and should just chill out.
And have his dinosaur body slam the other one.
Ten out of ten, great moral.
Our software engineer is about to show this hardware engineer the business
Then he gets a distress email. The worst way to send a distress message. Use a bottle!
They've walked into so many traps and they never work. So they're pretty confident
T.K. finds his crest, and a room filled with code.
Izzy's like: Bitches, I'm about to drop the fattest exposition dump, with holograms and everything.
Izzy explains they are in a digital world.
He uses a lot more words, but that's pretty much it
Then he uses fast travel, because he can do that now.
And only now. There's ElvisMon's desktop!
And inside, his IT guy who sent the distress email.
They are about to free him, but hold it
What are you doing in my custom PC, you pre-built buyers?
They fight. Sora gets kidnapped. And Tai has an existential crisis in the middle of fighting
Sora has been taken to the basement to be cloned
They have to rescue her, but how?
Oh right, their enemies have some animals and they have artillery
So they start a bombardment and they kill everyone!
Then monkey solos everything and heads back to the pyramid.
Sora! Ahaha! The copy is finished. I will now slowly give her the Digi-devices.
I can't believe you destroyed my plans by running!
Trap door!
That is ElvisMon's cable management. If you end up in there, it will be tangled for all eternity
Okay. This is my own fault. I give up
So Elvis attacks the IT guy and they both fall into the cable management, and this makes him super powerful
I don't know why. I rewatched it in three languages. I'm just gonna roll with it
It's all useless, but Tai has been mentally unstable for five episodes now
And he finally snaps and decides to charge. This bravery brought on by insanity!
Finally causes his Digimon to evolve into late 90's CGI Heromon! Breast missiles!
Destroys him, and Tai get sucked in.
Did he die?
Maybe
Find out on the next part of Digimon
Garbage Retrospective
Where we encounter the real worst enemy...
When Elijah had finished dubbing the entire series, he sent to Saban International
who were gonna publish it. I bet some of you hardcore Digimon nerds wanted to comment
Saban created the Digimon dub, not 4Kids.
This is you right now.
Finish the video before commenting
But Saban told 4Kids it's too perfect. It's the 90s.
We need to ruin it with a Digirap! The worst enemy of dubbed Digimon. And that is the kilian experience.
Longest video I've ever made
But a very requested video and the sequel should be here sooner, rather than later
Please press the bell and go on the subreddit